<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<Defs><ConceptDef ParentName="NotedOpportunisticBase">
    <defName>LLResearchRequirements</defName>
    <label>Research proficiency requirements</label>
    <helpText>Some research projects may require a colonist to have certain proficiencies in order to participate in researching. For example, a colonist may need to understand Geology and Electronics in order to research geothermal power sources. A project's requirements may be seen when selecting the project, and warnings will be displayed when attempting to research something that none of your colonists are capable of researching. \n\n
Because researchers will eventually run into proficiency requirements, it is a good idea to spend time teaching at least one researcher many science and technology related proficiencies.
    </helpText>
  </ConceptDef>

  <ConceptDef ParentName="NotedOpportunisticBase">
    <defName>LLLeadResearcher</defName>
    <label>Lead researcher</label>
    <helpText>While some colonists may not be able to help research a project due to proficiency requirements, they will be able to contribute as long as at least one qualified researcher is actively working. It may be helpful to assign a qualified colonist that would not normally be a good researcher to the research work type, so they can assist your less qualified but more talented colonists in finishing the project. As long as a qualified colonist is assigned to the research work type - and is not working on higher priority tasks - other researchers will join even if they do not have the prerequisite proficiencies.
    </helpText>
  </ConceptDef>

  <ConceptDef ParentName="NotedOpportunisticBase">
    <defName>LLMedicalRequirements</defName>
    <label>Medical qualifications</label>
    <helpText>In order to treat most basic injuries, a colonist must be trained in First Aid. In order to perform most surgeries or treat major or internal wounds, a colonist must be trained in Medical.\n\n By default, a colonist assigned to doctoring will not treat wounds and illnesses for which they do not have the requisite training to safely treat. This may be overridden by navigating to the Doctor's health tab and enabling "Tend All". \nBeware, as allowing a colonist to treat wounds they're not qualified to tend is very likely to make things much worse; Though it may be preferable to death. Wounds tended by an untrained person are much more likely to result in infection.
    </helpText>
  </ConceptDef>

  <ConceptDef ParentName="NotedOpportunisticBase">
    <defName>LLRecipeRequirements</defName>
    <label>Bill proficiency requirements</label>
    <helpText>Some bills require certain proficincies to perform, and an unqualified colonist will not work on them.
Qualifications may be viewed in the bill requirements panel after selecting a recipe.
In some cases, a bill may be worked without the required proficiencies, with a workspeed or quality penalty.
    </helpText>
  </ConceptDef>

  <ConceptDef ParentName="NotedOpportunisticBase">
    <defName>LLBuildingRequirements</defName>
    <label>Building proficiency requirements</label>
    <helpText>Some buildings require certain proficiencies in order to be constructed - For example, Electronics are needed for most electrical devices. \n
      Requried proficiencies may be viewed in the info panel when selecting a building. \n
In some cases a project may be built without the required proficiencies with a workspeed or quality penalty.
    </helpText>
  </ConceptDef>

  <ConceptDef ParentName="NotedOpportunisticBase">
    <defName>LLCommsRequirement</defName>
    <label>Comms console qualifications</label>
    <helpText>Operating a communications device capable of hailing orbital vessels requires a basic understanding of computer operation - and the ability to speak. \n
      Colonists who do not have the Speaking or Computers proficiencies will not be able to operate the Comms Console.
    </helpText>
  </ConceptDef>

  <ConceptDef ParentName="NotedOpportunisticBase">
    <defName>LLSpeaking</defName>
    <label>Learn to speak!</label>
    <helpText>Language is necessary to communicate with others, trade, use the comms console and more. \n
      Colonists who have not yet learned to speak will be unable to effectively communicate with others. This will not stop them from trying, however. \n
      These colonists will eventually learn to speak through interacting with others.
    </helpText>
  </ConceptDef>

  <ConceptDef ParentName="NotedOpportunisticBase">
    <defName>LLRareProficiency</defName>
    <label>Uncommon knowledge!</label>
    <helpText>There is a non colonist on the map that knows the Medical or Electronic proficiencies. These are vital proficiencies to have for any expanding colony.

Consider carefully how to deal with this stranger, as it may be worthwhile to "acquire" them.
    </helpText>
  </ConceptDef>

  <ConceptDef ParentName="NotedOpportunisticBase">
    <defName>LLLessonPlanToolIntro1</defName>
    <label>Learn about scheduling classes</label>
    <helpText>Now that you have a place for classes to be held, you can assign a class schedule to the newly built desk or teaching spot by selecting the building
      and clicking on the highlighted schedule button. \n\n
      You will need to first create a new class schedule by navigating to the Lessons tab highlighted below.
    </helpText>
    <highlightTags>
      <li>MainTab-LessonSchedule-Closed</li>
      <li>LL-Teacher-LessonSchedule-Gizmo</li>
    </highlightTags>
  </ConceptDef>

  <ConceptDef ParentName="NotedOpportunisticBase">
    <defName>LLLessonPlanToolIntro2</defName>
    <label>Lesson plan tutorial</label>
    <helpText>Click the highlighted button for a brief walkthrough of the Lesson Plan UI at any time.</helpText>
    <highlightTags>
      <li>LL-PlanTool-TutorialStart</li>
    </highlightTags>
  </ConceptDef>
</Defs>
