<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<LanguageData>
  <LLLearningTabLessons>Lesson Planning</LLLearningTabLessons>
  <LLLearningTabPioneering>Pioneering</LLLearningTabPioneering>
  <LLLearningTabMentoring>Mentoring</LLLearningTabMentoring>
  <RequiredSoftLabel>Soft Requirements</RequiredSoftLabel>
  <RequiredSoftDesc>Soft requirements will not prevent a colonist from working on this building or recipe, but may impose additional penalties.</RequiredSoftDesc>
  <UnqualifiedWorkspeedPenaltyLabel>Unqualified workspeed penalty</UnqualifiedWorkspeedPenaltyLabel>
  <UnqualifiedWorkspeedPenaltyDesc>If a colonist does not have all of the required proficiencies, the final workspeed will be multiplied by this value.</UnqualifiedWorkspeedPenaltyDesc>
  <UnqualifiedQualityCapLabel>Unqualified max quality</UnqualifiedQualityCapLabel>
  <UnqualifiedQualityCapDesc>If a colonist does not have all of the required proficiencies, the quality of the finished building or item cannot exceed this value.</UnqualifiedQualityCapDesc>
  <RewardedProficienciesLabel>Proficiencies taught</RewardedProficienciesLabel>
  <RewardedProficienciesDesc>These proficiencies may be trained by working on this building or recipe.</RewardedProficienciesDesc>
  <DeconstructProficienciesAwardedLabel>Deconstruct proficiencies taught</DeconstructProficienciesAwardedLabel>
  <DeconstructProficienciesAwardedDesc>These proficiencies may be trained by deconstructing this building.</DeconstructProficienciesAwardedDesc>

  <RequiredProficienciesLabel>Proficiency Requirements</RequiredProficienciesLabel>
  <RequiredProficienciesDesc>The knowledge required to perform this recipe.</RequiredProficienciesDesc>
  <LetterGainedProficiencyLabel>{0} Mastered</LetterGainedProficiencyLabel>
  <LetterGainedProficiency>{PAWN_labelShort} has mastered {1}</LetterGainedProficiency>
  <EarnedByCrafting>Earned by crafting:</EarnedByCrafting>
  <EarnedByDeconstructing>Earned by deconstructing:</EarnedByDeconstructing>
  <EarnedByBuilding>Earned by building:</EarnedByBuilding>
  <RequiredToCraft>Required to craft:</RequiredToCraft>
  <RequiredToBuild>Required to build:</RequiredToBuild>
  <RequiredToResearch>Required to research:</RequiredToResearch>
  <EarnedByTeachingLabel>May be taught.</EarnedByTeachingLabel>
  <EarnedByTeachingDesc>This proficiency may be taught by someone who already knows it.</EarnedByTeachingDesc>
  <AllowUntrainedTendingLabel>Tend All</AllowUntrainedTendingLabel>
  <AllowUntrainedTendingDesc>Colonist will attempt to tend conditions they are not qualified to tend. This may be dangerous.</AllowUntrainedTendingDesc>
  <NoTeacher>No teacher.</NoTeacher>
  <TeacherLabel>Teacher</TeacherLabel>
  <StudentLabel>Students</StudentLabel>
  <LessonPlanProficienciesLabel>Proficiencies in Lesson Plan</LessonPlanProficienciesLabel>
  <EffectivenessLabel>Effectiveness</EffectivenessLabel>
  <learnedLabel>Learned</learnedLabel>
  <learnableLabel>Can learn</learnableLabel>
  <SchedulerLabel>Class Scheduler</SchedulerLabel>
  <None>None</None>
  <PracticalExperience>Practical Experience</PracticalExperience>
  <TheoreticalExperience>Theoretical Experience</TheoreticalExperience>
  <PracticalLabel>Practical</PracticalLabel>
  <TheoreticalLabel>Theoretical</TheoreticalLabel>
  <PreferredLabel>Preferred</PreferredLabel>
  <FilterLabel>Filter</FilterLabel>
  <ActivityConsumesTargets>Consumes targets!</ActivityConsumesTargets>

  <WorkstationsLabel>Workstations</WorkstationsLabel>
  <StudyTargetsLabel>Study Targets</StudyTargetsLabel>
  <ProficiencyAlreadyKnown>{PAWN_labelShort} already knows {1}</ProficiencyAlreadyKnown>
  <LackingPrerequisites>{PAWN_labelShort} lacks prerequisites to learn {1}</LackingPrerequisites>
  <PrettyStorageStoredItems>Inventory</PrettyStorageStoredItems>


  <TeacherXpText>Base xp/hour: {0}
Teacher intellectual contribution: {1} xp/hour
Total xp/hour: {2}</TeacherXpText>
  <TeachXpTooltip>The amount of total XP awarded to each student before other effectiveness factors. Total amount is split between all proficiencies being taught.</TeachXpTooltip>
  
  <TeacherEffectivenessText>Overall effectiveness: {0}</TeacherEffectivenessText>
  <TeacherEffectivenessTooltip>This represents the functional effectiveness of this teacher based on their speaking and consciousness capacities.</TeacherEffectivenessTooltip>
  <EffectivenessTooltip>Base effectiveness: {0}
Subject limit before penalty: {1}
Effectiveness loss per excess subject: {2}
Student limit before penalty: {3}
Effectiveness loss per excess student: {4}</EffectivenessTooltip>
  <PioneeringDescribedText>Pioneering allows a colonist to "discover" a proficiency on their own through tireless effort over a long period of time.\n When assigned to pioneer a proficiency, each day the colonist will perform an assortment of learning activities depending on the proficiency being learned. Some activities require consumable resources, but most activities have no requirements or do not consume the items or buildings being studied. Each activity will generate a small amount of practical or theoretical experience when completed, and may only be repeated a certain number of times each day.\nActivities may be disabled by clicking the checkmark in the top corner of each activity card.\nWhen assigned to pioneeer, a colonist must be assigned to the "Research" work type before they will perform any activities. Once properly setup, they require no additional interaction or input to carry out their daily activities - as long as they have the necessary work stations to study at.\n\nPioneering is one way to learn an uncommon proficiency, but it is a very slow method. Using proficiency Neurotrainers, learning from another colonist, or simply recruiting someone who already knows the proficiency will all be much more efficient uses of time. In many case, even directly disassembling buildings or working on recipes will generate practical experience much faster. Consider carefully if the time investment is worthwhile.
</PioneeringDescribedText>

  <!-- Gizmos -->
  <NoScheduleLabel>No Schedule</NoScheduleLabel>
  <ScheduleGizmoDesc>Select a class schedule for this room.</ScheduleGizmoDesc>
  <CancelClassGizmo>Cancel Class</CancelClassGizmo>
  <CancelClassGizmoDesc>End the class early.</CancelClassGizmoDesc>
  <LeaveClassGizmo>Leave Class</LeaveClassGizmo>
  <LeaveClassGizmoDesc>Leave the classroom to do other tasks.</LeaveClassGizmoDesc>

  <!-- Settings -->
  <SettingsBaseXpPerHour>Base Teaching XP/hour</SettingsBaseXpPerHour>
  <SettingsBaseXpPerHour_desc>The amount of xp distributed per student over one hour of class attendance.</SettingsBaseXpPerHour_desc>

  <!-- Dev tools-->
  <PatchedTooltip>This def is already patched either directly or through the use of an inherited patch.</PatchedTooltip>
  <UnpatchedTooltip>This def is not patched.</UnpatchedTooltip>

  <!-- Generated defs -->
  <TextbookItemLabel>Textbook ({0})</TextbookItemLabel>
  <TextbookItemDescription>Though some might view a textbook as an archaic means of transferring knowledge, this book contains everything one might need to grasp the fundamentals of the subject on the cover. Detailed explanations, practice problems, answer keys, and more. \n\nWhen stored on a shelf in a classroom, students will automatically take relevant study materials to boost the effectiveness of their lessons.</TextbookItemDescription>

  <ProficiencyNeurotrainerLabel>neurotrainer ({0})</ProficiencyNeurotrainerLabel>
  <ProficiencyNeurotrainerUseLabel>Use neurotrainer to learn {0}</ProficiencyNeurotrainerUseLabel>
  <ProficiencyNeurotrainerDescription>A one-use super-dose of mechanites which teaches a specific expertise.\n\nThe dose is administered through the orbit of the eye. Once released into the brain, the mechanites "reprogram" a portion of the brain to generate new knowledge on the subject, transmuting themselves into neural tissue as needed.</ProficiencyNeurotrainerDescription>
  <ProficiencyNeurotrainerUsed>{USER_labelShort} used {1} neurotrainer to learn {2}.</ProficiencyNeurotrainerUsed>
</LanguageData>
